Nikema Prophet

An entry-level, language agnostic, software developer with over 20 years of experience as a technology enthusiast. My most recent focus is on frontend JavaScript development. I'm looking for my first technical position preferably in a community or people role. I am seeking remote positions, but I'm willing to relocate for the right opportunity. My preferred locations are SF/Bay Area, Sacramento, CA, New York, NY, and Atlanta, GA. Pronouns are: she/her/hers.

github.com/prophen https://nikema.dev nikema.prophet@popschools.com linkedin.com/in/nikemaprophet

PROJECTS - https://nikema.dev/portfolio/

<u>Small Wins</u> — Built with Express.js, MongoDB, Svelte.js, and Twilio APIs

<u>A-Z Experiences</u> — Team project built with React.js and Semantic UI

<u>Empowered Conversations: Landing Page</u> — Built with HTML, CSS/Less, JavaScript as a contribution to the team project

EXPERIENCE

PopSchools, Inc., Sacramento, CA — Founder/CEO

OCTOBER 2017 - PRESENT

- PopSchools provides a suite of products and services to allow for flexible work & living for tech-enabled families.
- Created branding and built a web presence, including social media and email list

Code for Hood, Sacramento, CA — *Instructor*

APRIL 2019 - MAY 2019

- Taught teens in a summer session about personal branding, content creation, and entrepreneurship.
- Responsible for lesson plans, classroom management, and submitting invoices for payment

Code for Hood, Sacramento, CA — *Instructor*

FALL 2017

- Created and facilitated an 8-week course on entrepreneurship.
- Was responsible for twice weekly classes, creating and submitting lesson plans, and attending team meetings.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools

Visual Studio Code, Vim, Git

Database Management

Relational Databases, SQL, MongoDB, MySQL, MS Access

Languages/Frameworks

JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Swift, React.js

Web Servers/Serverless Deployment

Deploying applications to Netlify, Heroku, ZEIT, Firebase, Google Cloud, Cloud

EDUCATION

<u>Lambda School</u> -Summer Hackers Program

May 2019 - August 2019

Completed Coursework Includes:

- User Interface and Git
- Advanced CSS
- JavaScript Fundamentals
- Applied JavaScript
- React
- Single Page Applications

<u>Sacramento City College</u> Sacramento, CA — *Web Developer Certificate*

2007 - 2012

Completed Coursework Includes:

- Database Programming
- Designing Accessible Websites
- Middleware Web Scripting
- Object Oriented Programming JAVA